hey guys welcome to this isosceles
triangle video so we're going to solve
for
x in this isosceles triangle the whole
idea of an isosceles triangle is that
these base angles are equal
and the sides opposite of those base
angles are going to be equal
and since these two sides are equal we
can set their expressions equal to each
other
so we can say 3x plus 5 equals 5x plus
1.
it says solve for x so our goal is get x
by itself
when we're done it should look something
like x equals something
a number but right now we have an x on
both sides of the equation we can't have
that so we're going to move 1 to the
other side
so i like to find the smaller of the 2
and the 3x is smaller than 5x
so i'm going to subtract that from both
sides the reason i do the smaller one is
because when i do 5x
minus 3x i get positive 2x and i prefer
positive numbers over negative numbers
and then this goes away so we're left
with just
5 on the left side and we have 2x plus
1.
now we only have one side that contains
an x
our goal now is to get that x by itself
so first i'm going to subtract the 1.
5 minus 1 is 4 and this all cancels so
we just have 2x
on the right side and now this means
two times x so the way i'm going to undo
that is divide both sides by two
and we get x equals two is the answer
and we can check it
so we got this one right so that's how
these work when you're trying to solve
for x and you're dealing with isosceles
triangles you usually will just set
the two sides equal to each other so
here's another variation
once again it's an isosceles triangle
and so we know the base angles are equal
and the sides are equal well here
they're telling us the degrees of the
angles so we can just set these degrees
equal to each other we can say
x minus 10 equals 50. now this
parenthesis doesn't mean anything
really because it's already alone on
that side so we just get rid of it once
again this says
solve for x so our whole goal is get x
by itself right now there's a minus 10
the way we undo a minus 10 is adding 10
which leaves us
x on the left side and 50 plus 10 is 60.
so the answer to this one should be x
equals 60 and we can check it
and it says the answer is x equals 60.
if you want to try more of these i have
this page on andymath.com i'll include a
link down below in the description
there's also related pages for more
triangle related concepts and these all
have practice problems and answers as
well
please like this video and subscribe to
my channel and comment below if you have
any other math questions i'll try to
answer them for you
i'll talk to you guys soon bye